Ahmed Habeila

Front-end web developer

☑ HabeilaAhmed@gmail.com

[] (647) 797-0872

🕥 Github **in** LinkedIn 🖳 Portfolio

ABOUT

I am a software engineer with 4 years of professional experience, mainly in front-end development using React.

I worked on various projects and dived into a lot of concepts of front-end development, from content-driven websites focused on accessibility and SEO to data-driven web apps with complex forms, data-rich charts and tables, reusable UI components and design systems. I have experience in **leading other developers**, reviewing their work and enforcing certain patterns, project-specific standards and **best practices**.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-end Web Developer November 2020 - January 2023

mber 2020 - January 2023

Working full-time for more than two years on this project, I led a team of 3 to 4 front-end developers in the process of creating and maintaining features while setting design system standards for the design team to follow.

Projects:

Calqulate: A financial tool for modern SaaS organizations that automatically generates reports on finances, growth metrics, cashflow forecasting, cash management, customer growth and churn, multi-source subscription management and more. Features complex editable tree tables with fixed columns, sticky headers and advanced styles, interactive data rich charts. Collects data from most known major accounting softwares. My biggest responsibility in this project is to create and maintain different libraries in a monorepo for tables, charts and reusable UI components.

Technologies used

React TypeScript Material UI Sass Styled components react-hook-form Zod D3 Hasura Stripe Payment Gateway GraphQL Auth0 Turborepo Sentry

What I worked on

Front-end Web App

Full-stack Web Developer

Nav 2020 - November 2020

Working as a full-stack web developer in varying projects using different sets of technologies. I've gained the most experience working here, tackling more challenging problems.

Projects:

<u>BMW Foundation</u>: Built this website from the ground up until it went live, it's an informative website of the foundation's mission, plans and events. The website features advanced accessibility features and multi-language routing.

Technologies used

React Gatsby TypeScript Material UI JSS Multi-language Routing Responsive Design I18Next Axios

What I worked on

Website (front-end)

<u>TwentyThirty</u>: Built this one from the ground up, it's an online magazine managed by the BMW Foundation inspiring a just and sustainable future in alignment with the UN 2030 Agenda.

Technologies used

React Gatsby TypeScript Material UI Responsive Design JSS Axios

What I worked on

Website (front-end)

Educational platform: An educational platform where professors can upload and schedule lectures to different classes, automatically create and share Zoom meeting links after a lecture have been seen by all the students to discuss it, create assignments, quizzes and grade students. We built two mobile apps for Android and iOS, an admin dashboard where professors can manage lectures, send emails with grades to students' parents.

Technologies used

Firebase Express.js TypeScript Sendgrid React Material UI JSS Formik Yup Axios

What I worked on

Back-end (Firebase) Admin Dashboard (front-end)

Full-stack Web Developer

May 2019 - May 2020

Netjeek: First project I've worked on that's went live, it's trans-shipping system designed to facilitate the purchase and delivery of goods to countries where customers can't place an order to international e-retailers directly.

Technologies used

React Javascript Material UI JSS Express.js Global State with React hooks Stripe Payment Gateway I18Next Axios JSON Web Token Google Maps

JSDoc Jest Enzyme

What I worked on

eCommerce Website (front-end) System Analysis Mock API creation

SKILLS & TOOLS

React 18
TypeScript
Material UI
Node.js
Git

Jira JSS/Styled components Data fetching
Localization Forms & validation Responsive Design
Unit Testing JSDoc Global State Design
Express.js Firebase MongoDB JWT

JS/HTML/CSS Python C++ Vue Solid JS

LANGUAGES

Arabic (Native) English (Fluent)

Coformatique

Hava Solutions Inc.

SELF-TAUGHT COURSES

Mastering React (by Mosh Hamedani)

Node.js - The Complete Guide to Build RESTful APIs
(by Mosh Hamedani)

Vue - The Complete Guide (w/ Router, Vuex, Composition API) (by Maximilian Schwarzmüller) CSS - The Complete Guide (by Maximilian

Master C. L. a

Master C++ and OOP (Learncpp.com) Introduction to Game Development Specialization (Coursera)

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree of Computer Science and Automatic Control

Faculty of Engineering - Tanta University 2014 - 2019

GRADUATION PROJECT

An Express-like C++ web application framework

A simple-to-use web development framework with an easy syntax inspired by Express.js that lets developers build full-fledged back-end multi-threaded api servers and connect it to the desired database in C++ that also supports middleware.

C++17 CGI Apache Multithreading Linux